Guide to the Donald N. Levin classics papers, 1947-1991 MS 046
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Donald Levin papers
1947-1991
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Levin, Donald N.
MS 046
6 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
This collection contains papers, articles, theses and "An Unorthodox Diary", which includes his perspective on the controversy over the brief presidency of Bill Masterson at Rice University, 1969, among many other topics. Also included in the collection are files regarding Classics courses taught by Dr. Levin at several universities as well as research notes on Classics subjects.
Biographical Note
Donald Norman Levin was born on February 1, 1927, in Rochester, New York. He received a bachelor's degree in French Literature and a master's degree in Classics from Cornell University, and then went on to Harvard to receive a doctorate degree in Classics. Dr. Levin taught at Cornell, Reed College, Harvard, Washington University and Mount Holyoke College before moving to Houston to teach at Rice. Dr. Levin arrived at Rice University in 1963, and would remain a Rice professor for 28 years. He produced a large volume of work during his career, including two books, two monographs, and several translations of classical works. He also authored numerous papers, over 30 of which were presented at classical society meetings and published in anthologies. He was a poet as well as a research writer, and sixteen of his poems were published. Dr. Levin died on November 23, 1991 at the age of 64.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers, articles, theses and "An Unorthodox Diary", which includes his perspective on the controversy over the brief presidency of Bill Masterson at Rice University, 1969, among many other topics. Also included in the collection are files regarding Classics courses taught by Dr. Levin at several universities as well as research notes on subjects in Classics. Additionally, there are two binders that contain memos and newsclippings related to events at Rice in the 1960s.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift donated by Ronald and Amy Baum ca. 1992.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Education
Document Types
articles; theses; diaries
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University -- History
- Series I: Correspondence, 1955-1971, 255821
  - Levin Correspondence: Personal/Political, Departmental, 1955-1971, 255823 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Levin Correspondence and history of L'Affaire Masterson (Masterson Controversy), An Unorthodox Diary, 1969, 255822 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Rice University newsclippings binders, 1964-1970, 255818
  - Binder containing materials (newsclippings, memos, etc.) related to controversies at Rice University from 1964-1969, 255820 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Binder containing materials related to various issues concerning Rice University, 1969-1970., 255819 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series III: Classics notes and works, 255565
  - "Concerning Two Odes of Horace", 255817 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Horace…Stylistic Observations", 255816 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Three Approaches to an Interpretation of Horace's Fifth Ode", 255815 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hylas, 255814 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Two Hylas Narratives", 255813 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Classics 3359; Fall 1975, 255812 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ovidius, 255811 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Paleography, 255810 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 225, 255809 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pindarus, 255808 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Plato, 255807 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pre-Socrates, 255806 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Propertius, 255805 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sophocles, 255804 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Greek 395; Fall 1951 – Cornell University, 255803 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stoici, 255802 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tacitus, 255801 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Theocritus, 255800 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Thucydides, 255799 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence between Tibulus and other poets, 255797 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Tibulus, 255798 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tibulus' death, 255796 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Tragedia, 255795 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Latin 112 B, 255794 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Latin 200, 255793 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Latin 205, 255792 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Latin 206, 255791 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Latin 221-222-321; Fall 1950, Spring 1951, Fall 1951, 255790 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Latin 300, 255789 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Latin 309, 255788 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Latin 309; Fall 1960-1961, 255787 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Latin 315-316-317; 1950-1951, 255786 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Latin 347, 255785 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Latin 410, 255784 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Latin 410, 255783 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Latin 410B, 255782 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Latin 410A, 255781 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Latin 412, 255780 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Latin khf, 255779 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Linguistics, 255778 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Literature 8; Spring 1947, 255777 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Literature 207, 255776 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Literature 207 – II, 255775 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Literature 241, 255774 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - English Literature 241, 255773 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Literature 401, 255772 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Literature 402, 255771 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Misc., 255770 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Harvard Misc., 255769 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Misc., 255768 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Sociology, 255767 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sociology 101, 255766 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Gen. ed., 255765 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Latin 315, 255764 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - English Literature 242, 255763 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Latin 412, 255762 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Latin 315, 255761 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Latin 309; 1962-1963, 255760 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Latin 102, 255759 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Latin 1322, 255758 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Humanities II, 255757 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - History 242, 255756 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - History 241, 255755 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - History 241-242, 255754 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - [Rice] General, 255753 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Greek, 255752 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - English 329 (Barbara Levin), 255751 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Greek B1-B2; 1959-1960, 255750 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Greek II, 255749 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Greek B21-B22; 1959-1960, 255748 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Greek 112b, 255747 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Greek 200, 255746 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Greek 201; Fall 1951, 255745 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Greek 209-210-309; Fall 1950; Spring 1951; Fall 1951, 255744 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Greek 217; 1959-1960, 255743 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Greek 301; Fall 1950, 255742 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Greek 302, 255741 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Greek 302; Spring 1951, 255740 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Greek 303, 255739 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Greek 304, 255738 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Catalogued, 255737 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Greek 305; Fall 1960-1961, 255736 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Greek 305-306; 1959-1960, 255735 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Greek 306; Spring 1960-1961, 255734 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Greek 307-308; Fall 1960-1961, 255733 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Greek 309, 255732 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Greek 490, 255731 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Greek 311-312, 255730 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Greek kht, 255729 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hebrew, 255728 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - History 241-242 (folder 1/3), 255727 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - History 241-242 (folder 2/3), 255726 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - History 241-242 (folder 3/3), 255725 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Humanities II – Reed College, 255724 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Fiction (By Levin), 255723 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Tragic Heroism, 255722 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Erinna, 255721 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Subjectivism, 255720 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Summary of Dissertation, 255719 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Thesis 1st Draft Part 3, 255718 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Thesis, 255717 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Drafts of a pg. 12, 255716 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Aeschylus, 255715 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Aeschylus – TTepac – Atteipon, 255714 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Levin Summary of Doctoral Dissertation, 1957, 255713 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tragic Heroism of Eteocles, 255712 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Review of Murray's The Motif of 10 in Aeschylus' Suppliants, 255711 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notes, 255710 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anaxagoras and his Colleagues, 255709 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Apollonius Rhodius (folder 1/2), 255708 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Apollonius Rhodius (folder 2/2), 255707 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Apollonius Rhodius: correspondence (folder 1/2), 255706 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Apollonius Rhodius: correspondence (folder 2/2), 255705 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Aristoteles, 255704 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Apollonius Rhodius A125, 255703 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Two Hylas Narratives, 255702 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bibliographies, 255701 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Callimachus, 255700 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Catullus, 255699 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ambiguities of Expression in Catullus, 255698 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Chariton, 255697 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cicero, 255696 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Drama, 255695 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Elegeia, 255694 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Myth and Subjectivism in Roman Elegy, 255693 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Epicurus and Lucretius, 255692 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Epigraphy with Prof. Bloch, 255691 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Quaestiones Erinneanae, 255690 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Euripides (folder 1/2), 255689 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Euripides (folder 2/2), 255688 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Development of Classics – Mount Holyoke College, 255687 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Hellenistica, 255686 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Hellenistic Philosophies, 255685 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Croesus as Ideal Tragic Hero, 255684 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Silente Tiberio, 255683 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Faculty council 1991, 255682 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Longus and the Development of the Pastoral Tradition – A Thesis presented by Frederick Charles Christie, Harvard University, 255681 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Untitled file, 255680 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cornell notebook, 255679 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Discarded 1st draft, 255678 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Spring 1960 grades, 255677 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Appointments, Promotions, Tenure, 255676 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Greek 411, 255675 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Greek 311, 255674 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Greek 303, 255673 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Latin 102, 255672 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Greek B22, 255671 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Greek B2, 255670 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Greek B1, 255669 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - English 330, 255668 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - English Literature 65-242, 255667 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - English Literature 241, 255666 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Classics 220, 255665 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Greek 217, 255664 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Classics 218, 255663 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Student exams, 255662 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ricordi Meridionali, 255661 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Apollonius Rhodius: A Reappraisal, 255660 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Moral dilemmas article, 255659 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Euripedes, 255658 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Newsclips, notes, 1958, 255657 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - An Unorthodox Diary, 1969-1973 drafts, 255656 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
  - Thesis Feb. 1952 (folder 1/2), 255655 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Thesis Feb. 1952 (folder 2/2), 255654 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Thesis 1st draft, 255653 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Notes, 255652 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Slim Volume for Me, In a style quite free, 1945-46, 255651 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Projects, 255650 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Thesis 1st draft, Part 2, 255649 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - An Unorthodox Diary extracts, 255648 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Hellenistic Echoes in Propetius' First Elegy", 255647 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - War and Peace in Early Roman Elegy, 255646 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Cunningham's edition of Hero(u)das, 255645 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Greek 492B, 255644 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Apollonius Rhodius, 255643 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Inventory of Extant Writings, 255642 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Racine's Deviations from Euripidean Precedent", 255641 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Thesis Draft, 255640 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Thesis, 255639 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Racine's Deviations from Euripidean Precedent" as submitted for publication in Comparative Literature – rejected, 255638 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lev NREL files – numerous, 255637 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Annotations, Tragicae, Comicaeve, Selectae, 255636 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "The Possible Impact of Roman Literature on Certain Ancient Novelists Who Wrote in Greek", 255635 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Various Papers/Articles by Levin, 255634 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Carmina/Carmi/Poemes/Gedichte 1959-1968, 255633 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Various Papers/Articles by Levin, 255632 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence regarding submissions/articles, 255631 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Proposal for Sabbatical to work on "Two Greek Novelists: Chariton and Longus, 255630 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Untitled file, 255629 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Levin AARI First Version: Introduction, Chapters I-XIV, Appendices A-D, 255628 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Levin AARI First Version: notes to Introduction, Chapter I-XIV, Appendices A-D; Bibliography, 255627 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ethical Implications of the TTepac-ATTeipon Dichotomy as Seen Particularly in the Works of Aeschvlvs, Levin, 1956, 255626 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ethical Implications of the TTepac-ATTeipon Dichotomy as Seen Particularly in the Works of Aeschvlvs – Thesis, 255625 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ancient Greek: An Introduction, 255624 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - An Unorthodox Diary, 1966, 255623 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
  - "Some Observations Concerning Plato's Lysis", 255622 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Linda Eichblatt; personal journals, travel journals, 255621 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Untitled file, 255620 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bibliographies Zum Antiken Roman, 255619 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notizen Zum Griechischen Roman I – XV, 255618 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Opvscvla Philologica 73-…, 255617 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Opvscvla Philologica 34-72, 255616 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Numerous Post-doctoral writings, 255615 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - General 1987-1988, 255614 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General 1985-1986, 255613 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Levin Biographical, 255612 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Chariton, 255611 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Drafts of Papers – Cornell, 255610 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - English – Monroe High School, 255609 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Re: Cornelia Coulter, 255608 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondences between Tibulus…2nd draft, 255607 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Introduction for Aristotle's Metaphysics, 255606 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ethical Implications…1st draft, 255605 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Tibulus, 255604 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Guggenheim Plan/Application, 255603 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, 255602 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Greek/Latin Exams 1953-54, 255601 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Two Hylas Narratives – Uncorrected, 255600 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - French (Columbia), 255599 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Shakespeare, 255598 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - English 302 (Spring 1947) and English 307 (Fall 1947), 255597 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Classical Philology 299A Term paper, 255596 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - French, 255595 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - General Education A, 255594 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Classical Philology 299A, 255593 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Classics 219, 255592 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Cultural Anthropology, 255591 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - English 251, 255590 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Classics 317-318, 255589 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Literary Criticism, 255588 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - English 25B, 255587 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Classics 318, 255586 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Auto mileage and highway notes for trip in Northwest U.S., and Greek notes, 255585 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Classics Majors, 255584 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Classics 32, 255583 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Classics 206, 255582 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Classics 219-200 1960-61, 255581 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - French Literature 19th e. 1948 Columbia, 255580 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Anthropology, 255579 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Assignments and bibliography, 255578 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - French survey, 255577 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - French, 255576 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - French 202, 255575 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - French 362, 255574 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - French 18th and 19th century, 255573 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Herooas, 255572 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Hesiodus, 255571 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Homerus, 255570 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Horatius, 255569 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Classical Philology 299B, 255568 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Classics 300, 255567 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Euripides, 255566 (Box 12, Folder 45)